Hi there, and welcome.
In this video I'm just gonna
talk briefly about an interface.
So an interface is something that you can add
to a class to give it a little bit more, more
in a set of rules that you want to use or maybe
just a blueprint for that particular object.
So here I have a couple of pets
I've got a bat and I've got a bird.
They both show share similar characteristics.
However, a bat is a mammal
and a bird is, well, a bird.
Um, I, I'm not stated what type
of bird we're dealing with.
So you could actually class, um, the bird class
as being a, a parent class to certain other birds
like Budgerigar, Parrot and that sort of thing
and then dig down a little bit further on those.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna show
you how to create an interface in Java.
So first of all, we go to our source and we
right click and go to new and I'm gonna create
a Java class, so I'm gonna hit that now in telli
J it breaks it down for me, I'm gonna choose the
interface and I'm going to choose flying like so.
So I'm gonna call my class flying, okay?
So this is a public interface called
flying, and what I want to do is I
want to create a method which is just
basically the bird flying simple as that.
So what we do is we create an abstract glass, just
like we did in the pet area, and I'm gonna create
an abstract glass called flight speed, okay, now
I need to give it a little bit more information.
So we'll make it public and void so it doesn't
return anything but just like with the, just need
to put the capital S because we're using Camel
case, When I create an abstract method like this,
um, I don't actually put any information into it,
so it's just gonna be flight speed, that's fine.
Now let's go back to our bat, here we go.
Now the bat currently extends the PET class,
but it can also implement the flying class.
Now, as soon as I've done that, it's gonna say I
must create that abstract method, flight speed.
So let's come down to here and we'll create
that medicine public void flight speed
uh, because we're dealing with a bat.
I'm just gonna say all over the place.
I don't know if you've seen bats, but
they don't tend to fly in a straight line
they tend to zigzag all over the place.
Now the bird also flies as well, well, I'm
gonna assume that this particular one does
cuz birds generally can or cannot fly.
If you take an Ostrich or an Emu you, for example,
that's not gonna fly but we will say that this
particular one does, so implements flying.
There you go, okay, and again,
I need to put in a method.
So let's do that public
void and it's flight speed.
And I'm just gonna do, um,
let's see, 30 miles per hour.
I'm sure they probably go a lot faster than
that, but this is just for the exercise okay?
So what I've done is I've
used the implements, okay?
Now if I go to my dog class, my ,dog
class doesn't fly I'm not gonna implement
the flying class into here, the flying
interface, because dogs don't fly and again,
that doesn't interfere with my PET class.
So my pet class can stay that as it has been.
Just by creating a number of interfaces, I can
set rules, the thing is, the difference between
an interface and say the actual class itself, and
when you implement those class, or rather when
you extend those classes, is I can have as many
interfaces as I want for each of the classes.
Let's think what, what else can a bird do?
Um, so a bird might be able to swim all right.
Now Bats can't swim, but some birds can swim.
So let's have another class so I'll come
over to here, create a new class and just
call it swims interface, and I'll just create
a very simple method it'd be an abstract
method and it's going to be public and void.
Cause we're not returning anything and I'm just
gonna call it swim like, so, so now I can go to
my bird and I can say it also implements swims.
Okay, now I'm gonna need to add that method to it.
So let's do that.
So public void swims, and I'm
just gonna say, Oh, let's just do
something very basic so splish-splash.
Well actually the dog, let's
go to our dog class a moment.
The dog can also implement
swim because dog swims too.
Let's make this a little bit easier cuz I've
got swims as a class, but the method is swims.
So let's go to our class moment and
just change that to swim like so and
I just need to make a quick change.
Let's do that, show context and I'm
gonna rename the file so it's swim.
I'll also need to go to my back class.
Let's do that, and make sure that, Oh, back
class actually, it's not the back class is it?
It's the bird class.
Make sure that is implementing the swim that's
still able to do the swims, which is fine.
Go to the dog class then we might be going,
There you go and what I'll do is public void,
swims, paddle, those dogs are known to paddle.
All right?
So again, I'm able to use the interface on
associated classes that match the requirement.
So I've got a flying interface and I've
got a swim interface, and both of those are
implemented through several of my classes.
So when you want to set rules for specific
classes, but not all classes falls into those
rules, then what you need to do is set up an
interface to being able to utilize that benefit.
Okay.
Hopefully you've learned something
from this and I will see you again.
Thank you.